Inventory of the Great Britain Ministry of Information propaganda
Hoover Institution Archives
Great Britain Ministry of Information propaganda
1938-1949
XX229
Hoover Institution Archives
17 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 1 oversize folder (7.8 linear feet)
Pamphlets, posters, serial issues, press releases, photographs, and postcards, distributed during World War II.
Great Britain. Ministry of Information.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Formed on September 4th 1939, the day after Britain's declaration of war, the Ministry of Information (MOI) was the central government department responsible for publicity and propaganda in the Second World War. The initial functions of the MOI were threefold: news and press censorship; home publicity; and overseas publicity in Allied and neutral countries. Planning for such an organisation had started in October 1935 under the auspices of the Committee for Imperial Defence, largely conducted in secret; otherwise the government was publicly admitting the inevitability of war. Propaganda was still tainted by the experience of the First World War. In the ‘Great War', several different agencies had been responsible for propaganda, except for a brief period when there had been a Department of Information (1917) and a Ministry of Information (1918) Planning for the new MOI was largely organised by volunteers drawn from a wide range of government departments, public bodies and specialist outside organisations. In March 1946, the MOI was dissolved. Its residual functions passed to the Central Office of Information (COI), a central organisation providing common and specialist information services.
Source: "The Art of War" The National Archives, Great Britain, http://www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/theartofwar/inf3.htm
Scope and Content of Collection
The propaganda collection includes a variety of materials distributed during World War II by the Ministry of Information in Great Britain. The various pamphlets, leaflets, posters, serial issues, press releases, photographs, and postcards include: informational guides that explain how to set up bomb shelters, what to do in a fire, what crops to grow, and what the public can do to help keep themselves and others safe. The collection also contains newspapers and brochures discussing the current situations throughout the war; counter propaganda materials that combat the influence of Nazi propaganda; and materials that highlight new British inventions and breakthroughs such as improved planes, submarines, and combat tactics. A majority of the materials have visual images such as cartoons and drawings. Some materials are duplicates printed in multiple languages.
The container list below is arranged by format in two groups: Pamphlets and Leaflets, and Maps, Portraits, Postcards, and Stamps, then alphabetically by title of the document. Author, publisher, and publisher location are listed when available on the document. Dates are given when they appear on the item, otherwise dates are supposed to be within the years of World War II. Materials in each box are physically arranged in alphabetical order by title.
Propaganda, British.; World War, 1939-1945--Great Britain.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.
- Pamphlets and leaflets, 1938-1949
  Arranged alphabetically by title on the document. Author, publisher, and publisher location are listed in sequence when available on the document. Dates are given when they appear on the document, otherwise dates are supposed to be within the years of World War II.
  - "10 German Blunders" (Box 1)
  - "100 Facts about The United Kingdom's War Effort," British Ministry of Information, London, 1945 (Box 4)
  - "100 fatti dello sforzo bellico della Gran Bretagna," Ministry of Information (Box 9)
  - "15 de Septiembre de 1940" (Box 16)
  - "17 American Naval...," Pillans & Wilson, Edinburgh, Great Britain (Box 2)
  - "2 Crucial Points of Allied Attack!" (Box 5)
  - "50 Facts about Social Services in Britain," British Information Services, U.S.A. (Box 3)
  - "50 Facts about the Colonies," K.H.K. (Box 9)
  - "50 Facts about the Middle East," British Information Services, New York, 1944 (Box 1)
  - "50 Facts about the Women of Britain at War" (Box 9)
  - "A bord d'un bombardier géant" (Box 3)
  - "A bord d'un sous-marin Britannique" (Box 17)
  - "A los 25 años," Stevens & B. (Box 4)
  - "A Woman's Place Now" (In the A.T.S.), Cockayne & Co., Ltd. and Curwen Press (Box 6)
  - "Adult Education," Ministry of Information (Box 6)
  - "Aerial Bombardment: The Facts" (Box 6)
  - "Africa: The Summing-up" (Box 1)
  - "African Victory with the British Forces," British Information Services, New York City (Box 2)
  - "Aggrey of Africa," B & M Ltd. (Box 7)
  - "A agricultura em Inglaterra," Sir John Russell, Stevens & B (Box 16)
  - "La agricultura en pie de guerra" (Box 10)
  - "Agriculture in Britain," British Information Services, U.S.A., 1947 (Box 1)
  - "Les ailes de l'empire" (Box 14)
  - "The Air Offensive Against Germany" (Box 16)
  - "Air Raid Precautions Training Bulletin No. 1," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1940 (Box 6)
  - "Air Raid Precautions Training Bulletin No. 2," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1940 (Box 6)
  - "Air Raid Precautions: War Time Lighting Restrictions for Industrial and Commercial Premises," His Majesty's Stationary Office, London (Box 17)
  - "The Air Raid Warning System," Ministry of Information & Ministry of Home Security, England (Box 4)
  - "Al ataque!" (Box 9)
  - "Alas del imperio" (Box 11)
  - "Alemão-Nazi em 22 lições" (Box 8)
  - "All on the Job" (Box 1)
  - "All These Countries Were Promised Hitler's 'Eternal Friendship'" (Box 3)
  - "Alocuciones y documentos referentes a la declaración de guerra," Ministry of Information, London, 1939 (Box 16)
  - "L'amiral Darlan," Cheuvillon, 1946 (Box 1)
  - "Another 50 Facts about Britain at War," British Information Services, New York City, 1943 (Box 2)
  - "Another Nazi Propaganda Trick!" England (Box 4)
  - "Appeal" (Box 6)
  - "Apply for an Emergency Grant," S & C Ltd. (Box 9)
  - "Arbeiders voor de vrijheid" (Box 10)
  - "Armed Forces Rankings" posters (Box 10)
  - "L'armée Britannique aujourd'hui" (Box 17)
  - "L'armée Britannique" (Box 13)
  - "Arrived Safely--" H.M. Stationery Office, England (Box 5)
  - "The Art of Lying" Adolph Hitler and Joseph Goebbels, (in English, Spanish, and French) (Box 3)
  - "As Hitler Sowed...," England (Box 2)
  - "At War Against the Axis" (Box 16)
  - "El ataque desde el aire" (Box 11)
  - "The Atlantic Charter" (Box 2)
  - "The Atlantic Meeting" (Box 7)
  - "Aunknoopen van vriendschapsbanden," Hodder & Stoughton Ltd., London (Box 10)
  - "Awards to Volunteers from Eire Serving with the British Forces" (Box 7)
  - "The Battle for Civilization," K.H.K. (Box 5)
  - "The Battle of the Atlantic," Holland, James (Box 5)
  - "The Battle of Blizzards," British Information Services, New York City, 1947 (Box 10)
  - "The Battle of Britain: August-Ocober 1940," Harrison & Sons Ltd. (Box 3)
  - "The Battle of Production," Hazell, Watson & Viney Ltd., England (Box 2)
  - "The Battle of Supplies," Hodder & Stoughton Ltd., London (Box 7)
  - "The Battle of Supply" (Box 10)
  - "BBC," BBC (Box 3)
  - "Be Prepared to Defend the Peace We're Working to Win," Central Office of Information, Great Britain (Box 8)
  - "Beating the Invader," Ministry of Information (Box 12)
  - "'N Belg beskrywe sy indrukke van Brittanje se oorlogspoging" (Box 10)
  - "Belgen bestrijden Hitler" (Box 8)
  - "Belgian Congo" (Box 1)
  - "Belgie in oorlog: 21 Julie, 1940," London (Box 10)
  - "La Belgique en guerre contre Hitler" (Box 8)
  - "La Belgique en guerre: le 21 Juillet, 1940," London (Box 10)
  - "Een Belgische meening over Groot-Brittannie's oorlogsinspanning" (Box 8)
  - "Belgium's War Against Hitler" (Box 3)
  - "Berlin and Now London" (Box 5)
  - "De bestorming door de lucht" (Box 11)
  - "Bitwa nad wyspami Brytyjskimi," Ministry of Aviation (Box 10)
  - "Bombardeamentos aeros" (Box 1)
  - "Books and Freedom Exhibition," Clemence Dane, Alabaster, Passmore & Sons, Ltd., London (Box 3)
  - "Books of Freedom Exhibition," A. Duff Cooper, P & S., Ltd. (Box 5)
  - "The Brains to Win" (Box 5)
  - "Britain Acts," England (Box 4)
  - "Britain and India," R. Coupland, Longman's Green & Co., Ltd. (Box 7)
  - "Britain and South Africa," Eric A. Walker, Longman's Green and Co. Ltd., London (Box 2)
  - "Britain and the United Nations," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1948 (Box 7)
  - "Britain Can Take It...and Give It Back," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London (Box 7)
  - "Britain Shows the Flag," K.H.K., England (Box 3)
  - "Britain's Air Offensive Grows!" Fosh & Cross Ltd. (Box 8)
  - "Britain's Air Offensive: Occupied France" and "Britain's Air Offensive: 'Halifax' Bombers over Berlin" (Box 9)
  - "Britain's Air Power," Eyre and Spottiswoode Ltd., England, 1940 (Box 3)
  - "Britain's Airborne Forces" (Box 11)
  - "Britain's Democratic Strength" (Box 6)
  - "Britain's Guns" (Box 2)
  - "Britain's Industrial Achievement: Behind the Fighting Fronts" (Box 2)
  - "Britain's Mechanised Army" (Box 4)
  - "Britain's Royal Air Force" (Box 13)
  - "Britain's Sea Offensive," Harrison & Sons Ltd., 1941 (Box 12)
  - "Britain's Social Services: Today and Tomorrow," Arthur Wauters (Box 4)
  - "Britain's Two Navies" (Box 10)
  - "Britain's War Effort Through the Eyes of a Belgian" (Box 6)
  - "Britian's War Economy," Ministry of Information (Box 9)
  - "British Air Offensives" (Box 14)
  - "British Air Victories," Odhams (Watford) Ltd., 1941 (Box 5)
  - "The British Ally (No. 35)" (in Russian), 1943 (Box 10)
  - "British and German Science in War-Time," Sir Thomas H. Holland, England (Box 2)
  - "The British Army Makes a Lightning Advance in North Africa" (Box 16)
  - "The British Army" (Box 10)
  - "The British Churches in War Time," Hugh Martin, The Ministry of Information, London, 1944 (Box 1)
  - "The British Colonial Empire and the British Public," Vincent Harlow, London (Box 3)
  - "British Commandos" (Box 14)
  - "The British Commonwealth of Nations," Keliher, Hudson and Kearns. Ltd., London (Box 2)
  - "The British Commonwealth," Issues 3,4,and 5, Harrison & Sons Ltd., London, 1940 (Box 13)
  - "The British Commonwealth, 2. Dominion Status," J.A. Wiliams, Harrison & Sons Ltd., London, 1940 (Box 14)
  - "British Constitutional Monarchy," Sir Ernest Barker, Oxford University Press (Box 6)
  - "British Democracy in War Time," Mary Agnes Hamilaton, Fosh & Cross Ltd., London, 1945 (Box 16)
  - "The British Empire's King and Queen," Keliher, Hudson & Kearns, Ltd., England (Box 7)
  - "British Foreign Policy," K.H.K. (Box 3)
  - "British Guiana for Victory," Cockayne & Co., Ltd. (Box 8)
  - "British Honduras for Victory," Cockayne & Co. Ltd. (Box 5)
  - "British Justice," Sie Maurice Amos, Longman's Green and Co. Ltd., Great Britain, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "British Military Information" posters, 1943 (Box 14)
  - "British Sea-and-Air Power" (Box 2)
  - "The British System of Governement," W.A. Robson, Longmans Green & Co., London, 1940 (Box 7)
  - "British Trade Unions and the War," John Price, British Ministry of Information, London (Box 10)
  - "British Universities Line Up for War," England (Box 2)
  - "British Women at War," Ministry of Information (Box 6)
  - "British, French and German Warships at a Glance," Sampson, Low, Marston & Co., Ltd., England (Box 4)
  - "De Britsche kerken in oorlogstijd," Hugh Martin, Ministry of Information (Box 17)
  - "Het Britsche leger" (Box 11)
  - "Britska armada" (Box 13)
  - "Brittanje se lugvervoerde troepe" (Box 14)
  - "Brittanje se twee vlote" (Box 14)
  - "Broken Homes" (Box 1)
  - "The Budget and Your Pocket," His Majesty's Stationery Office, Great Britain (Box 1)
  - "Cadran" No. 22 (Box 16)
  - "Call to Youth," England (Box 8)
  - "The Calm Before the Storm," Neville Chamberlain, England, 1940 (Box 2)
  - "Canada," H.M. Stationery Office, London (Box 4)
  - "Canada's War Record," Director of Public Information, 1942 (Box 10)
  - "Care and Custody of Equipment," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1940 (Box 9)
  - "Care and Custody of Respirators," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1940 (Box 9)
  - "Careless Talk Costs Lives:...But for Heaven's Sake Don't Say I Told You" (Box 9)
  - "Careless Talk Costs Lives: Be Careful What You Say and Where You Say It!" (Box 9)
  - "Careless Talk Costs Lives: But Of Course It Musn't Go Any Further" (Box 4)
  - "Careless Talk Costs Lives: Don't Forget That Walls Have Ears!" (Box 9)
  - "Careless Talk Costs Lives: Of Course There's No Harm in Your Knowing..." (Box 4)
  - "Careless Talk Costs Lives: Strictly Between These Four Walls!" (Box 9)
  - "Careless Talk Costs Lives: Strictly Between You and Me...." (Box 4)
  - "Careless Talk Costs Lives: You Never Know Who's Listening" (Box 9)
  - "Carrying On" (Box 3)
  - "A Catalogue of Crime," B & M Ltd. (Box 6)
  - "The Catholics of Britain at War" (Box 10)
  - "Ce qu'ont fait les Anglais," Ministry of Information (Box 9)
  - "Censorship of Postal Packets Sent from Great Britian to Nothern Ireland and Eire, and from Northern Ireland to Eire" (Box 3)
  - "Ceylon for Victory," Cockayne & Co., Ltd. (Box 8)
  - "Ceylon: Part I, The Island of Ceylon," Ministry of Information (Box 6)
  - "Ceylon: Part II, Its People and History," Ministry of Information (Box 6)
  - "Ceylon: Part III, Progress under British Rule," Ministry of Information (Box 6)
  - "Ceylon: Part IV, Ceylon's Part in the War" Ministry of Information (Box 6)
  - "Challenge To Youth," Lord Halifax, England, 1940 (Box 4)
  - "Children Into Ruffians," H.M. Stationery Office (Box 5)
  - "Children of Europe..." (Box 9)
  - "La cité de Londres," Stevens & B, 1946 (Box 16)
  - "Citizens Advice Notes: 13-18," The National Council of Social Service, London, 1940 (Box 8)
  - "Citizens Advice Notes: 19," The National Council of Social Service, London, 1940 (Box 3)
  - "Citizens Advice Notes: 20," The National Council of Social Service, London, 1940 (Box 8)
  - "Citizens Advice Notes: 22-23," The National Council of Social Service, London, 1940 (Box 8)
  - "The City of London" (Box 17)
  - "Civil Defence Uniforms," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1944 (Box 6)
  - "Civil Service," His Majesty's Stationery Office (Box 7)
  - "The Colonial Effort," Harold MacMillan, K.H.K., 1942 (Box 5)
  - "The Colonies At War," Times Publishing Company, Ltd., London, 1940 (Box 4)
  - "Los commandos" (Box 9)
  - "De commandos," England (Box 8)
  - "Comment l'Angleterre fit la guerre," Stevens & B, 1946 (Box 16)
  - "A Commentary on Herr Hitler's Speech of September 19, 1939" (Box 3)
  - "Commonwealth In Arms," Harlow, Vincent, Eyre & Spottiswoode Ltd., England (Box 4)
  - "Commonwealth Murals, No 1" (Box 11)
  - "Communication With Prisoners of War and Civilians in Japan and Japanese Occupied Territories," General Post Office, 1944 (Box 13)
  - "Le complot Laval-Pétain," Complot Laval-Petain, Stevens & B. (Box 1)
  - "Comrades In Arms," Ministry of Information (Box 16)
  - "Conditions On the Continent" (Box 4)
  - "A Conflict of Youth," Times Publishing Company, Ltd., London, 1940 (Box 4)
  - "Conquer We Shall," Winston Churchill, England, 1940 (Box 10)
  - "Country Homes", 1943 (Box 9)
  - "The Daily Life of a District Commissioner's Clerk," B & M Ltd., England (Box 7)
  - "Das ende" (with English translation) (Box 5)
  - "A Day in the Life of a Native Treasury Scribe," B & M Ltd., England (Box 7)
  - "A Day in the Life of a Nigerian Emir," B & M Ltd. (Box 7)
  - "A Day in the Life of a Tanganyika Chief," B & M Ltd. (Box 6)
  - "The Day's Work of a District Officer in Nigeria," B & M Ltd. (Box 7)
  - "Deadly Dollars" (Box 8)
  - "Declaration For International Students Day," Keliher, Hudson & Kearns, London (Box 3)
  - "Declare..." (Box 7)
  - "Den engelske industris indsats bag fronten," His Majesty's Stationary Office, 1945 (Box 14)
  - "Der frieheitskampf," London, 1940 (Box 14)
  - "Desert Victory" (Box 5)
  - "Despierta un gigante!" (Box 9)
  - "Les deux croix de guerre du général de Gaulle" (Box 10)
  - "Les deux marines de l'Angleterre" (Box 12)
  - "Developments In The Economic Structure of the Co-Prosperity Sphere During the Past Year, Parts 1-2," Ministry of Information (Box 3)
  - "Deze namen maken overwinningen" (Box 10)
  - "Die britse leer" (Box 13)
  - "Dig for Victory," The Ministry of Agriculture and Fisheries, England (Box 3)
  - "Dig for Victory Now," H.M. Stationery Office, London (Box 3)
  - "The District Commissioner Settles a Tribal Dispute in East Africa" (Box 3)
  - "Do You Know What a German Victory Would Mean To Us?" (Box 2)
  - "Doctors of To-Morrow in the Pacific Islands," British Information Services; Fosh & Cross Ltd., New York City (Box 5)
  - "El dominio en Polonia," Godden, G.M. (Box 8)
  - "The Dominions of the War," Times Publishing Company, London, 1939 (Box 4)
  - "Drake's Drum," Foot, Isaac, Eyre and Spottiswoode Ltd., England, 1940 (Box 3)
  - "Duas cidades bombardeadas" (Box 8)
  - "De dunkerque au jour 'J'" (Box 13)
  - "Dutise industrie in vrede en oorlog" (Box 8)
  - "East Africa Army Corps" (Box 13)
  - "East Africa," Harrison & Sons Ltd. (Box 9)
  - "The East London Mosque and Islamic Culture Centre," Edgar G. Dunstan & Co., London, 1941 (Box 2)
  - "Economic News" (In Farsi with a map of U.S.) (Box 1)
  - "Economic Warfare," Minister of Economic Warfare, H.M. Stationery Office Press, England, 1940 (Box 5)
  - "Education in Britain," Ministry of Information (Box 10)
  - "Education in the British Army," B & M Ltd., Great Britain, 1944 (Box 7)
  - "L'éducation sous le régime Nazi," Stevens & B. (Box 1)
  - "Education Under Nazi Rule" (Box 7)
  - "L'effort de guerre du Canada," W.L. Mackenzie King, Le Service de L'Information, Ottawa, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "Eighty Million Germans," England (Box 4)
  - "Emergency Protection In Factories," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1940 (Box 6)
  - "The Empire At War" Issues No.2-7, 9, 11, 13-14 (Box 13)
  - "An Empire In Arms" (Box 2)
  - "Enemy Uniforms at a Glance," Ministry of Information, Fosh & Cross Ltd. (Box 2)
  - "The Englishmen," Earl Baldwin, Longman's Green & Co., London, 1940 (Box 2)
  - "L'Entente and the French Colonial Empire," The Franco-British Publishing Co., Ltd. (Box 3)
  - "L'Entente and the Man of Tomorrow," The Franco-British Publishing Co., London (Box 10)
  - "L'Entente Continues," Franco-British Publishing Company Ltd., Great Britain (Box 9)
  - "Entente cordiale," The Franco-British Publishing Co., Ltd., Great Britain (Box 9)
  - "Entente in Spite of Everything," The Franco British Publishing Co., Ltd., Great Britain (Box 9)
  - "Entrants to the Mining Industry," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1946 (Box 1)
  - "An Equal Chance," Passmore & Sons Ltd., England (Box 12)
  - "Er is vrijhead en de lucht," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1944 (Box 10)
  - "Europe After Four Years of German Domination," Ministry of Information, 1944 (Box 6)
  - "Eve em salopette," Arthur Wauters, British Information Services (Box 9)
  - "Eve in Overalls," Arthur Wauters (Box 9)
  - Extracts from the film "Coastal Command" (Box 3)
  - "The Face of Britain," L. Dudley Stamp, Longmans Green & Co., London (Box 8)
  - "Factories of Freedom" (Box 4)
  - "Factory Front," Councillor Jack Owen, National Committee, People's Convention (Box 10)
  - "Fall in Under Our War Work Flag," Ministry of Labour and National Service (Box 7)
  - "Family Guide to the National Insurance Scheme," His Majesty's Stationery Office (Box 8)
  - "Farmer's Easy Payment Plan," E & S, England (Box 4)
  - "Farmers! What to Do if the Invader Comes," Department of Agriculture for Scotland (Box 3)
  - "Farmers! What to Do if the Invader Comes," Ministry of Agriculture and Fisheries (Box 3)
  - "Federal Union News, April-May, 1940," Federal Union, London (Box 10)
  - "Federal Union News, February-March, 1940," Federal Union, London (Box 10)
  - "Fellow-Arabs!" (Box 7)
  - "Fellow-Muslims" (Box 7)
  - "Les femmes Britanniques en guerre" (Box 17)
  - "Festival of Nine Lessons and Carols,", 1945 (Box 13)
  - "Fifty Facts about Burma" (Box 9)
  - "Fifty Facts about India," K.H.K. (Box 10)
  - "Fighting Fit in the Factory," Ministry of Labour and National Service (Box 8)
  - "The Financial and Economic Situation of France," Herve Alphand, Editions de la France Libre Ltd., London (Box 9)
  - "Fire Guard Training Notes No. 1-5, 7," Ministry of Home Security (Box 13)
  - "Fire Prevention (Business Premises) Order, 1941," Ministry of Home Security (Box 3)
  - "The First Year of the War: 1939-1940," for the National Book Council by Maurice Marston, London, 1941 (Box 4)
  - Flag prints (various countries) (Box 14)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 1: When the R.A.F. Bombs Germany," England (Box 5)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 2: Into Action with British Paratroops," England (Box 5)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 3: Combined Operations," England (Box 5)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 4: Motor Torpedo Boats Sink a German Ship," England (Box 5)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 5: Civilian Soldiers Release Troops for Second Front," England (Box 5)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 6: Atlantic Patrol," England (Box 5)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 8: Offensive in the Desert" (Box 5)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 9: Victory in Egypt," England (Box 5)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 10: The Road to Tunis" (Box 5)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 11: Flies Over Africa, The Men Who Freed Africa from the Axis" (Box 5)
  - "The Flag of Victory No. 12, British Boys Volunteer for Air Training" (Box 5)
  - "Food For Thought," Ministry of Food (Box 4)
  - "The Four Red Lights," Ministry of Information, England (Box 4)
  - "Four Under Hitler" (Box 4)
  - "The Free Forces of Europe" (Box 1)
  - "Free French Forces," Harrison & Sons Ltd., England (Box 9)
  - "The Freedom We Defend," C.E. Hodges and H.V. Usill, The Sun Engraving Co., England (Box 16)
  - "Freedoms Fortress," Fosh and Cross Ltd., London (Box 13)
  - "Friends of the Fighting Forces," Sir Reginald Wingate, 1941 (Box 1)
  - "From Factory to Victory" (Box 9)
  - "From the British Empire to the British Commonwealth," Alfred Zimmern, Longman's, Green and Co. Ltd., London, 1941 (Box 2)
  - "Le front du travail" (Box 10)
  - "The Future of India," Sir Firoz Khan Noon (Box 3)
  - "Gas Detection and Identification Service," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1944 (Box 6)
  - "Un géant s'éveille!" (Box 9)
  - "Gefangenen gazette" (Box 14)
  - "Gems of German Propaganda" and "More Gems of German Propaganda," J. Weiner Ltd., England (Box 5)
  - "The German Aggression on Norway," H.M Stationary Office, England, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "German Defeat in 1918," Times Publishing Company, Ltd., London, 1939 (Box 4)
  - "German Industry Through Peace and War" (Box 1)
  - German leaflets to Allied troops (in German) (Box 5)
  - "German Mine-Laying (British Retaliation)" H.M. Stationery Office Press, 1939 (Box 3)
  - "German 'Peace'," Ministry of Information (Box 4)
  - "German Press Control in the Occupied Territories," Ministry of Information, London, 1941 (Box 9)
  - "German Workers Under Hitler's Heel," John Marchbank, England (Box 3)
  - "Germany's Real War Aims," Harold Nicolson, B.B.C., England, 1940 (Box 2)
  - "The Gestapo v. Christianity" (Box 17)
  - "A Giant Awakes!" (Box 9)
  - "Giants of the Air" (Box 4)
  - "¡Gigante que despierta!" (Box 9)